It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Jiraiyan told Musashi that Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan. But he couldn't believe that.
지라이얀은 무사시에게 히미코가 시라누이 일족의 여왕이라고 말했다. 그러나 믿기지 않는 일이었다.
By Jūbee's investigation, they found out that Shiranui Clan is the descendants of the Fire Country.
주베의 조사로 시라누이 일족은 불의 나라의 자손이라는 것을 알게 됐다.
But by Gaenma's attack, they fell into a crisis in an instant.
그러나 거기서 가엔마에게 당해, 아차하며 위기에 빠졌다.
Using that chaotic moment, Musashi disguises himself as Shiranui and infiltrates to them.
그 혼잡한 틈을 타서 무사시는 변장해 시라누이 일족으로 잠입한다.
The Queen of the Fire Country
불의 나라의 여왕
Himiko
히미코이오
Stop!
정지!
Hey, be careful!
어이, 조심해라!
I'm sorry-dasu.
아, 미안하오.
Are everyone here?
전원 모였는가!
Then, what follows the word Sakura?
그럼 사쿠라라고 하면?
-Sakurajima! -Sakuramochi!
-사쿠라지마! -사쿠마모찌!
S- Sakuramochi?
사, 사쿠라모찌?
Err, Sakuramochi is tasty-dasu.
아, 아니, 사쿠라모찌는 맛있소.
I love it-dasu!
나 정말 좋아하오!
Your password is different!
암호가 다르다!
Well, that's, I was too hungry and it came out-dasu!
아, 아니, 배가 고파서 절로 새어나왔소.
Sorry-dasu, sorry-dasu!
미안하오, 미안하오.
Sakura means Sakurajima-dasu!
사쿠라라고 하면 사쿠라지마이오!
Well, good enough! We're returning to our base Sakurajima right away, for our next mission!
뭐, 됐다! 우리는 다음 임무를 위해 즉시 본거지 사쿠라지마에 들어간다!
Come!
와라!
That's a relief-dasu. Then let me continue-dasu!
잘 됐소. 말 안해도 계속하오!
Kojirō.
코지로.
Senhime. I'm prepared as always.
센히메 님. 전 언제라도 갈 수 있습니다.
I'm ready, too.
나도 준비 OK야.
Jūbee!
주베!
I'll use my halberd to get rid of those Shiranuis!
시라누이 일족 따위 이 언월도로 엉망진창으로 만들어 주겠어!
Senhime.
센히메 님.
I was thinking that you should wait here, instead of going...
그냥 하는 말이지만, 공주님은 가지 말고 여기서 기다리시는 게...
I wanted to say that too, but...
저도 그렇게 말씀드리고 싶었습니다만...
That birdbrain fool Musashi must be heading to Sakurajima, smuggled into Shiranuis.
그 덜렁쇠 멍청이 무사시는 분명 시라누이 일족에 숨어들어가 사쿠라지마에 간 게 뻔해.
I agree. That's why you should...
그렇습니다. 그러니까 여긴...
That's why we all should go together to rescue that birdbrain fool by marching in!
그러니까, 그 덜렁쇠 멍청이 단고쟁이를 구하기 위해 우리가 갈 수밖에 없잖아?
I'm saying that we'll...
그러니까, 저희가...
Yes. We are going to rescue Musashi.
그래. 우리가 무사시를 구하러 가는 거야.
Wait for us, Musashi! Do not die! Live! Survive!
기다려라, 무사시! 죽으면 안 된다! 살아! 살아남아!
Never give up on your dream of becoming the number one martial artist of Jipangu, Musashi!
지팡구 제일의 무예가의 꿈을 버리면 안 돼, 무사시!
Senhime never listens to whoever it is...
센히메 님은 말해도 안 듣는 분이라서...
Never forget that we're going for you! Everyone are going for you! Musashi! Just you wait for us!
자, 알겠냐! 꼭 간다! 우리, 그리고 나 너 따라간다! 무사시! 기다려!
She was born in the Year of the Horse.
공주님은 분명 말띠.
I see. That's why she's bucking like a horse.
그렇군요. 그래서 말처럼 날뛰시는군요.
Everyone, are you ready?
여러분, 준비는 되셨습니까.
Yeah, completely!
아, 완전히!
Great.
좋소.
Then let's go-gowasu.
그럼 출발하오.
Alright! We're going to the base of Shiranui Clan, starting now!
좋아! 시라누이 일족의 본거지에 자, 가자!
Huh? Weren't we going to Sakurajima-dasu? Why aren't we riding boat-dasu?
어라? 우리 사쿠라지마에 가는 것 아니었소? 왜 배에 안 타오?
Are you a newcomer?
너 신입이냐?
Uh, well, that's right-dasu. I'm still learning things-dasu...
어, 저, 그렇소. 나 아직 수습 기간이어서...
Y- yeah-dasu! I didn't realize because I was loitering on the way-dasu!
그, 그렇소! 나 계속 길에서 딴짓해서 몰랐소!
Hurry!
서둘러!
Woah, it's gone in a blink of a eye-dasu!
이야, 눈 깜짝할 새에 안 보이게 되었소.
I told you to hurry!
서두르랬지!
I can't go back anymore-dasu.
이제 돌아갈 수 없게 되었소.
I never knew there was this kind of device in Sakurajima-dasu...
사쿠라지마 속에 이런 장치가 있었소...
And the base of Shiranui Clan.
그리고 시라누이 일족의 본거지.
It's burning-dasu!
타오르오!
What is it-dasu?
뭣이오?
Uh, nothing.
아, 딱히.
Lord Himiko!
히미코 님!
What Jiraiyan said was true-dasu.
지라이얀이 말한 건 사실이었소.
I never thought Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan...
히미코 씨가 시라누이 일족의 여왕이었다니...
Everyone! The time has come.
제군! 때는 왔다.
The time to revive Shiranui Clan, on this ground!
우리 시라누이 일족을 부흥할 때가! 지금 이 땅에!
Yessir, your majesty!
예, 여왕님!
Your majesty!
여왕님!
We, Shiranui Clan, began 2,000 years ago, as one blood of the Fire Country, working hard for prosperity.
우리 시라누이 일족은 지금에서 거슬러 올라가길 2000년. 불의 나라의 혈족으로서 번영을 바라며 일하고 있었다.
But that prosperity was short.
그러나 그 번영은 잠시였다.
Ever since then, people of the Fire Country has been roaming.
그 이래, 우리 불의 나라의 자들은 떠돌이 생활을 해왔을 뿐이었다.
But we had unswerving determination for 2,000 years!
그러나 고절! 고절 2000년! 지금이야말로 우리 시라누이 일족의 손에 돈으로는 얻을 수 없는 번영을 되찾을 때입니다!
We will rebuild the Fire Country of promised prosperity by our own hands.
이 손으로 약속된 번영의 불의 나라를 재건하는 것입니다.
For that, we have to take Jipangu State into our hands!
그걸 위해서는 이 지팡구 곡을 우리 수중에!
Yessir! Queen Himiko! Queen Himiko!
예! 히미코 여왕님! 히미코 여왕님!
T- this is a serious conspiracy-dasu!
이, 이건 대단한 음모이오.
Listen to me, everyone. A new comrade is going to help us for our revival.
제군. 잘 들어라. 우리 부흥을 위해 새로운 동료가 힘을 빌려주게 되었다.
Mr. Hanzō.
자, 한조 님.
Wha- Hanzō!?
에, 한조!?
H- Hanzō!
하, 한조!
I, Hanzō will do everything I can to help the revival of the Fire Country.
나 한조는 전력을 다해 불의 나라 재건을 돕겠다.
I knew that Hanzō and Himiko were...
역시 한조가 히미코하고...
Everyone! For our objective, Shiranui must move first and do an armed uprising to overthrow Jipangu State.
제군! 우리 목적을 달성하기 위해서는 먼저 시라누이 일족이 무장봉기하고 지팡구국을 전복시켜야 한다.
This really is serious, for that Hanzō to join forces with Shiranui Clan-dasu!
시라누이 일족에 한조가 가세했다니 큰일이오!
On the dawn of occupying Jipangu State, we will make people drudge
지팡국을 점령한 새벽에는 사람들을 걸레짝인 양 부려
to pay off old scores, and under the ruling of Queen Himiko,
지금까지의 원한을 풀고 히미코 여왕 아래서 시라누이 일족의 염원, 불의 나라를 장렬히 재건할 것이다.
Yessir!
예!
This is really bad-dasu.
정말 큰일났소.
I should not be deeply involved in this.
이건 깊이 개입하지 않는 게 나을 것 같다.
Stay put!
숨어 있어!
Lord Himiko is a great person.
히미코 님도 대단한 분이시다.
T- that's true-dasu.
그, 그렇소.
dasu?
~소?
Is this guy Musashi!?
얘 설마... 무사시?
Everyone! Make an oath of victory to Hanzō and me!
제군! 나와 한조에게 승리의 맹새를!
Yessir! Queen Himiko! Yesser! Mr. Hanzō!
예! 히미코 여왕님! 예! 한조 님!
Hmph. They're burning up just like fire, only because of a speech of this simplicity? What a simple-minded fools.
흥. 이 정도의 연설으로 참으로 불처럼 타오른다니 단순한 놈들이구나.
Lower your head! You're standing out, Musashi!
고개 숙여! 들킨다, 무사시!
I have to let everyone know about this as soon as possible-dasu!
이건 어서 모두에게 알려야 하오!
Where are you going!?
거기 너 어디 가나!
Er, well, that's, um... I was so excited that I now want to pee-dasu.
아, 아, 그게, 저... 왠지 흥분해서 오줌싸고 싶어졌소.
dasu?
~소?
Nonono, I'm going-gowasu.
아니아니아니, 가는 걸세다.
You fool...
바보 자식.
Show your face!
얼굴을 보여라!
N- no, this isn't a face worth being shown-dasu.
아, 아니, 보일 정도의 얼굴은 아니오.
Nono, gowasu!
아니라, 아닌걸세다!
Ahh! Stop it-gowasu!
아! 그만하시는 걸세다!
Musashi!
무사시!
No-dasu! -gowasu! I'm not Musashi-gowasu!
아니오! 인 걸세다! 나, 무사시가 아닌 걸세다!
Rightrightright, I was imitating that Musashi guy, but to be called as Musashi, I must be doing well-gowasu!
그래그래그래, 그 무사시라는 자하고 딱 닮게 흉내내고 있었는데 그렇게 불리다니 잘 되는가 보구려.
No excuse will get you out of that situation! Just run!
거기까지 들킨 주제에 뭔 변명이야! 어서 도망쳐!
Oh, you're claiming that you're not Musashi? Then take this!
호, 넌 무사시가 아니라는 거냐? 그럼 이걸 받아 봐라!
Idiot!
바보.
Thank you for the dumpling-dasu! Tasty!
만두를 주다니 감사하오! 맛있소!
Judging from the filthiness of that gluttony, that guy really is Musashi!
저 더러운 식탐을 보아하니, 저 놈은 분명히 무사시다!
Oh no...
저런...
Stupid Musashi.
멍청한 무사시.
Did you really give up your life for that dumplings, Musashi!? Wait for the stormy latter half!
만두를 위해 목숨을 내던졌냐, 무사시! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Musashi is over there.
무사시는 저기에.
Yes. But, Senhime, please think one more time before we go.
예. 다만, 센히메 님, 지금 다시 한번 생각을.
I keep my word.
제게 두말은 없습니다.
We might not be able to get back once we leave-gowasu.
출발하면 못 돌아올 지도 모르오.
Yes, but I'm living to my best everyday as if there is no tomorrow. That's why I do not have any lingering attachment.
예. 저는 매일매일을 말뚝 없는 듯 전력을 다해 살고 있습니다. 그러니까... 미련이 남는 건 하나도 없습니다.
Thinking about it, I have one attachment.
그러고 보니 하나 미련이 있습니다.
Princess, what is that?
공주님, 그건 무엇입니까?
I couldn't find a good male!
남자 못 찾은 거!
Hmph! You found me out, and then I'm going to deal with it-dasu!
흥. 들킨 이상 어쩔 수 없소!
Musashi! You were alive!
무사시. 너 살아 있었구나!
Hmph! I revived-dasu!
흥! 살아 돌아왔소!
You dared to deceive me-dasu, Himiko!
잘도 날 속였겠소, 히미코!
It means that you're a fool.
속은 네가 바보다.
It seems that your foolishness has not been fixed even after dying once.
한번 죽었어도 그 멍청한 건 안 고쳐졌나 보구나.
How dare you sneak into the base of Shiranui unconcernedly!
뻔뻔스레 시라누이의 본거지에 들어오다니 말이다!
That dauntlessness is my personality-dasu!
그 대담무쌍한 점이 내 성격이오!
Do not babble, you brat!
지껄이지 마라, 꼬맹아!
Damn!
젠장!
I will send you back to that world this time!
이번에야말로 저 세상에 되돌려 보내 주겠다!
What!?
뭣이!?
Jiraiyan!
지라이얀!
Musashi!
무사시!
I'm sorry-dasu, Jiraiyan. That Himiko really was the queen of Shiranui-dasu.
지라이얀, 미안하오. 역시 히미코는 시라누이 일족의 여왕이었소.
Forget about that; just run away!
이제 됐으니까 어쨌든 도망쳐!
I'll face them-dasu!
내가 상대해 주겠소!
Kill him! Kill!
죽여라! 죽여!
Jiraiyan, it's been a while!
지라이얀, 오랜만이다!
Why are you here?
너 왜 이런 곳에?
That's my line! Why are you with Shiranui?
그건 내가 할 말이다! 왜 네가 시라누이하고!
You'll know why soon. Only death waits whoever stands in our way! You showed yourself so that we won't have to find you!
답은 곧 알게 될 테다. 우리에게 칼을 든 자에게는 죽음만이 있을 뿐! 찾을 수고도 덜었다!
I'll deal with him.
이 놈은 내가 처리한다.
It is impossible for you to defeat me!
너 따위가 날 이길 수 있을 리가 없다!
What!?
뭣이!?
Who was that!?
누구이오!?
I, Jinnai, will pay back the resentment of Genba, Tenzen, and Gaenma!
겐바, 텐젠, 가엔마의 원수는 이 진나이가 갚겠다.
Huh!?
어라!?
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Damn!
젠장!
That's as far as you go.
거기까지구나.
Kerokichi!
케로키치!
Musashi! Please escape safely!
무사시! 잘 달아나라!
Your life is over, Musashi!
이제 끝이구나, 무사시!
How regretful-dasu.
무념이오.
Stop.
멈추십시오.
Lord Queen Himiko!
히미코 여왕님.
I will take care of that guy.
그 자는 제가 처리하겠습니다.
Mr. Musashi, you are misunderstanding.
무사시 씨, 당신은 오해하고 있습니다.
Misunderstand?
오해?
What do you mean by misunderstanding-dasu!?
오해라니 뭔 소리이오!
I am not your enemy.
나는 적이 아닙니다.
What-dasu? Nononono, I won't get deceived-dasu! You're trying to kill me again by saying that-dasu!
뭣이오? 아니아니아니아니, 속지 않소! 그런 소리를 해서 날 죽일 생각이오!
I don't do that.
저는 그런 일은 하지 않습니다.
Mr. Musashi, you told me that I'm just like your mother, right?
이전에 무사시 씨가 저를 보고 어머님 같다고 말씀하셨죠?
It hurts, it hurts!
아파, 아파!
Mommy, it hurts! Mommy, it hurts!
엄마, 아파, 엄마, 아파!
What's wrong, Musashi?
왜 그러니, 무사시.
That's true-dasu.
그랬었소.
I can't kill someone like that.
그런 분을 죽이다니.
I know you're hungry. Please eat.
자, 배고프죠? 어서 드세요.
Thank you-dasu! I knew that you really are kind-dasu!
아, 감사하오! 역시 히미코 씨는 친절하오!
Tasty, tasty, tasty-dasu! It's really tasty, tasty, tasty-dasu!
맛있소, 맛있소, 맛있소! 정말 맛있소, 맛있소, 맛있소!
Do you feel happy, Musashi?
자, 기분 좋아지셨죠, 무사시?
Yes...
네...
Can you see a beautiful flower?
자, 예쁜 꽃이 보이죠?
How many?
몇 개?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
When the flames disappear, Musashi is mine. Understand?
불꽃이 사라지면 무사시는 제 것. 알겠어요?
Yes-dasu.
네이오.
Musashi? Musashi?
무사시? 무사시?
Musashi. Listen to whatever I say.
무사시, 제가 말하는 것은 무엇이든 들으세요.
Yessir. Musashi will listen to whatever Lord Queen Himiko says-dasu.
네. 무사시는 히미코 여왕님이 말씀하시는 것은 무엇이든 듣소.
You will work for me much more from now on, since you managed to revive at great pains.
당신은 아직 많이 일해야 할 것입니다. 기껏 살아 돌아오셨으니.
Yessir. Since Musashi managed to revive at great pains, he will work for Lord Queen Himiko-dasu.
네. 무사시는 기껏 살아 돌아왔으니 히미코 여왕님을 위해 일하오.
Good.
좋아.
We're already at the base of Shiranui. The enemy can come to attack us without notice.
여기는 벌써 시라누이의 본거지. 언제 적이 덮쳐들지 모릅니다.
Do not let your guards down-gowasu.
방심은 금물이오.
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Musashi! You're safe!
무사시! 무사했구나!
What's wrong, Shiro?
왜 그러나, 시로!
Kill. Kill.
죽여라. 죽여라.
Musashi!
무사시!
Musashi! What are you doing!?
무사시! 뭔 짓을!
Kill. Kill. Kill!
죽여라. 죽여라. 죽여라!
Mr. Musashi! Wake up!
무사시 씨! 정신 차리십시오!
The one to stop Kojirō, who came with a firm resolve to lay down his life to rescue Musashi, was - no way! -
필사의 각오로 무사시를 구하러 온 코지로 앞에 막아선 자는, 무슨! 히미코의 요술에 걸려 살인 병기가 되고 만 무사시였다.
Is the only choice for Kojirō and others to fight Musashi with swords?
코지로 일행은 무사시하고 칼로 싸워야만 하는가?
Everyone on Kojirō's side is in a crisis, but so is Musashi!
코지로 일행도 위기지만 무사시도 또다시 위기!
How will this end up!?
과연 이 결판은 어찌 나는가!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
I fought Kojirō and others because of the magic of Ms. Himiko.
히미코 씨의 요술으로 코지로 일행하고 싸운 나.
Ms. Himiko really is a bad person-dasu.
역시 히미코 씨는 나쁜 사람이오.
But even worse is that Hanzō-dasu!
그래도 더 나쁜 건 그 한조이오!
That guy is trying to smash a huge missile into Satsumania-dasu!
놈도 참, 거대한 미사일을 사츠마니아에 들이박을 작정이오!
Satsumania will be annihilated at this rate-dasu!
이대로라면 사츠마니아가 전멸하고 마오!
Next story! The Last Conspiracy of Shiranui
다음 이야기! 시라누이 최후의 음모이오
It's a stormy big explosion-dasu!
질풍노도의 대폭발이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
The Last Conspiracy
시라누이 최후의
of Shiranui
음모이오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!